{"data":[{"question":"He _____ in that country for five years when I first met him.","a":"had lived","b":"was living","c":"lived","d":"had been living","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (he lived there and may countinue living after i first met him) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"The Titanic _____ on the sea bed for 70 years when they found it.","a":"had been laying","b":"had lain","c":"had been lying","d":"had laid","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (The ship lied there and may continue lying there after they found it) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"Luke _____ in the Navy for six months when he had the accident.","a":"had been serving","b":"had served","c":"was serving","d":"had serviced","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous:\n+Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (He served in the Navy and may countinue serving there after the accident)\n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"They _____ trees all afternoon when I saw them.","a":"had planted","b":"had been planting","c":"were planting","d":"had picking","answer":"2","explain":"\n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (They planted tree and may continue planting after I saw them \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"We all knew he _____ whiskey again. He stank.","a":"was drinking","b":"had been drinking","c":"drank","d":"is drinking","answer":"2","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous before another action in the past is a good way to show cause and effect: \nDrink- stank \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"When I got to the beach my wife _____ in the sun for two hours.","a":"was lying","b":"had lain","c":"will have been lying","d":"had been lying","answer":"4","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (She may coutinue lying after I got to the beach) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"When I met the old preacher _____ for 20 years in that Parish.","a":"he had been preaching","b":"had been preaching","c":"preached","d":"was preaching","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (He preached and may continue lying after i meet) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"The lonely couple _____ a son for a long time.","a":"had been wanting","b":"were wanting","c":"wanted","d":"are wanting","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past ( They continued wanting) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing ","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"When she arrived I _____ for ten minutes.","a":"will have waited","b":"waited","c":"had been waiting","d":"was waiting","answer":"3","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (I waited and may continue waiting when she arrived) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"},{"question":"When I got there they _____ felling trees for hours.","a":"had been","b":"had being","c":"were","d":"will have been","answer":"1","explain":"\n- Past Perfect Continuous: \n+ Show that something started in the past and continued up until another time in the past (They felt tree and may continue felling after I got there) \n+ Structure: S+ had + been +V_ing","category":"2","subcategorylv1":"15","subcategorylv2":"1","type":"1"}]}